Victor PATRIN

36 avenue des Maussants, 36130 Déols, France / +33 (0)6 78 71 53 26 / victor.patrin150@gmail.com

Objective

I am a 22 years old engineering student in computer science and a blockchain enthusiast in my spare time. Curious and motivated, I think we have so much to learn from others whether it be on personal, professional or cultural aspects.

• Education

Sept. 2018 – Present Master's degree in Computer Science – Faculty of Sciences and

Technologies, Nancy, France

Major in Information and Systems Security

Sept. 2016 – Present French Graduate School of Engineering - Ecole des Mines de Nancy

Major in Computer Science & IT

Sept. 2013 – Jul. 2016 Classes Préparatoires aux Grandes Ecoles – Lycée Gay-Lussac,

Limoges, France

Major in Advanced and Applied Mathematics, Computer Science & Physics

A 3- year undergraduate program for preparation to national competitive exams for admission to French most prestigious graduate schools of engineering.

July 2013 French Baccalauréat in Science / Physics (high school leaving diploma)

passed with Honours (14.6 / 20)

Professional Experiences

Oct. 2018 – Present **Junior Software Developer** at *Ubirch GmbH*, *Berlin*, *Germany*:

Flexible student contract of 40h per month until my final year internship

starts – Remote job

Missions: Implementation of data anchoring services on blockchains

June 2018 – Sept 2018 Internship as an assistant engineer at *Ubirch GmbH*, *Berlin*, *Germany*:

A "Blockchain for Things" start-up guaranteeing that IoT data is trustworthy and secure, using blockchain technology and military-grade cryptography

<u>Missions:</u> Mobile application used to verify cryptographic identities & Implementation of data anchoring services IOTA & Ethereum

Sept. 2017 – June 2018 **Research project** in the Computer Science & IT department: *Disassembly*

of .NET executable files and malware detection

<u>Purpose:</u> Developing a disassembler to extract a control flow graph from executable files & running a morphological analysis on a graph database

Oct. 2017 – Jan. 2018 **Research project** in mixed teams with a partner Business School:

Blockchain projects applicability in metropolises and smart grid

developments

Conducted during courses of Competitive Intelligence and Decision Making in which we learned about technology intelligence, sourcing and lobbying strategies in business and diplomacy

Feb. 2017 – Oct. 2017 Corporate Relation Officer at Forum Est-Horizon

Recruitment fair organized by Mines Nancy students (20 members), which gathers 50+ companies and welcomes 1000+ visitors every year

Feb. 2017 (1 month) **Internship as an operator** at *Société des Condensateurs Record*,

Montierchaume, France

Duties: Working on almost every step needed to manufacture a capacitor

Skills: Versatility

Oct. 16 – June 2017 **Treasurer of the project "Carton Solid'Air"** at *Enactus France*

(International student organization whose aim is the development of social

entrepreneurship Projects)

Project purpose: Sell/rent carboard furniture manufactured in rehabilitation

centers

Sept. 16 – June 2017 **FEDEEH Tutor** (National federation which assists young people with

disabilities in their professional training and work) Duties: Career counselling, homework support

Sept. 2015 – July 2016 **Research project** in the last year of my undergraduate program:

String similarity measurements and Kolmogorov complexity

<u>Purpose:</u> Using Kolmogorov complexity to set a shared information formula to calculate similarities between ASCII-converted pictures

Computer Skills

Languages: Python, C, C++, Java, SQL, R (data analysis), C#, JavaScript, Matlab,

PHP, HTML, CSS, LaTeX, JavaScript frameworks (Ionic & Cordova)

Operating Systems: GNU/Linux, Windows, macOS

Languages

French Native

English Fluent, C1 - IELTS 7.5/9 (June 2017)

Spanish: Intermediate – Preparation of DELE B1 (Dec. 2018)

Miscellaneous

Travels: Oct. 2018: ten-day vacation in Montreal

Aug. 2017: a seven-day road trip in Transylvania, Romania and a week in

Ukraine (L'viv, Kiev, visit of the ghost town Pripyat and Chernobyl)

<u>Aug. 2015</u>: Interrail trip (Amsterdam, Berlin, Prague, Krakow, Budapest)

Interests: Philosophy – Chess – Videogames – Sport – Modern Art